For decades, scientists hypothesized that cognitively demanding tasks, such as writing or solving math problems, require more energy than easier tasks like scrolling short videos on the phone or looking out of the window.
几十年来，科学家们一直假设，写作或解数学题这类高认知要求的任务，比刷手机短视频或望着窗外这类轻松的任务更耗能量。
However, recent research proves the view wrong.
然而，最近的研究证明这种观点是错误的。
Our brains perform massively complex and metabolically costly computations all day long.
我们的大脑整天都在进行极其复杂、代谢成本很高的运算。
“Whether you’re engaged in a cognitively demanding task at work or you’re staring off into space, your brain is using roughly the same amount of energy,” says neuroscientist Todd Braver of Washington University in St. Louis.
“无论你是在工作中忙于一项费脑的任务，还是在发呆，你的大脑消耗的能量都大致相同，”圣路易斯华盛顿大学的神经科学家托德·布雷弗说。
In fact, what feels more challenging is when a task requires the brain to go against its usual habits.
事实上，让人感觉更有挑战性的，是任务要求大脑违背它惯常的习惯。
Cognitively demanding work often requires the coordination of many different brain regions in novel patterns, while silencing circuits that frequently fire together.
高认知要求的工作，常常需要大脑许多不同区域以新的模式协同运作，同时让那些经常一起被激活的神经回路安静下来。
Studies have found that pushing against our brain’s habits triggers an emotional response, making us feel uncomfortable.
研究发现，违背大脑的习惯会引发一种情绪反应，让我们感到不舒服。
“It’s aversive, and it just feels bad,” says Michael Inzlicht, a psychologist from the University of Toronto.
“这让人反感，感觉就是很糟糕，”多伦多大学的心理学家迈克尔·因兹利希特说。
But he points out that emotional responses are subjective: they are interpretations of sensations in our bodies and brains.
但他指出，情绪反应是主观的：它们是对我们身体和大脑中各种感觉的解读。
And we can influence how much we pay attention to these sensations and even how we interpret them.
而我们可以影响自己对这些感觉的关注程度，甚至可以影响我们如何解读它们。
We often overestimate the struggle and pain required to complete cognitive tasks.
我们常常高估完成认知任务所需的努力和痛苦。
This initial overestimation can lead us to procrastinate, or even avoid the task altogether.
这种最初的高估可能导致我们拖延，甚至完全回避这项任务。
Studies suggest that if we can get past that initial hurdle of starting a task, then thinking becomes easier.
研究表明，如果我们能越过开始一项任务时的最初障碍，思考就会变得更容易。
One way to do that is to pay attention to the benefits instead of the efforts required.
一个办法是把注意力放在回报上，而不是所需付出的努力上。
In a study published in the journal Science in 2020, Andrew Westbrook, a neuroscientist at Rutgers University, and his colleagues gave participants the choice of solving an easy memory puzzle for a small amount of money or a much harder puzzle for more money.
在2020年发表于《科学》杂志的一项研究中，罗格斯大学的神经科学家安德鲁·韦斯特布鲁克和同事让参与者选择：解一道简单的记忆题赚一小笔钱，或者解一道难得多的题赚更多钱。
The options were displayed on a screen, and participants’ eye movements were tracked as they decided which puzzle to attempt.
这些选项显示在屏幕上，在参与者决定尝试哪道题时，研究人员追踪了他们的眼球运动。
When people spent more time looking at the reward for the challenging puzzle, they were more likely to choose it.
当人们花更多时间去看那道难题的奖励时，他们就更有可能选择它。
If our mind’s eye, or our attentional focus, is on the benefits of an option, over time we’re more likely to choose to do hard things.
如果我们的“心灵之眼”，也就是注意力的焦点，放在某个选项的好处上，那么随着时间推移，我们就更有可能选择去做困难的事。
Performing complex mental tasks will also be less painful if the exertion of mental effort is habituated.
如果付出脑力成了一种习惯，执行复杂的脑力任务也就不那么痛苦了。
When we don’t have to make a decision to focus every day, we will save ourselves considering the costs or consequences.
当我们不必每天都下决心去专注时，就省得去考虑代价或后果了。
To make cognitively demanding tasks a habit, try to do them every day at the same time and in the same place.
要让高认知要求的任务成为习惯，试着每天在同一时间、同一地点去做。
Add a ritual before the work starts, such as turning off the phone and launching an app to block distracting websites.
在工作开始前加一个仪式，比如关掉手机，打开一个屏蔽干扰网站的应用。
After a few weeks, concentrating deeply won’t just feel easier, it will actually be easier.
几周之后，深度专注不仅会感觉更容易，而且真的会变得更容易。